Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Publications and Ephemera Collection AD.RG.002.1-1
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
NYU Abu Dhabi Publications and Ephemera
2010-2022
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG.002.1-1
8 Linear Feet in 22 legal-sized document boxes, 3 oversize folders
The NYU Abu Dhabi Publications and Ephemera collection consists of published bulletins, curricula guides, brochures, research reports, commemencement programs, class yearbooks, events catalogs and calendars, faculty and student journals, and a few commemorative artifacts, which document academic and community life across the NYU Abu Dhabi campus, including research achievements, from 2010 - present.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this Record Group have been acquired over time from a variety of sources, donated to the library, picked up by Library staff at events, donated or transferred from outgoing staff upon their exiting employment, and transferred as part of an annual routine transfer (such as Bulletins transferred by the Registrar's Office). The original accession number was 2014.003.
Publications from the following accessions have been integrated as accretions to this collection: Acc2019.014 (Dustin Harris), Acc2019.028 (Paul Revere), Acc2020.008 (Dustin Harris), Acc2021.028 (Kate Chandler), Acc2022.040 (Paul Revere), Acc2022.041 (Pauline Conaghan), Acc2023.007 (Chuck Grim), Acc2023.012 (Jacqueline Jacbos),
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series:
Admissions and Recruitment
Students
Research and Achievements
Core Curricula
Campus Bulletins
Campus departments, programs, events, journals
Artifacts
This collection is a "living" collection, and is regularly being added to. Users should note and pay attention to box numbers and order; while the materials are described and intellectually arranged by series, listed in alphabetical order in most cases, containers and box numbers may follow a different order that reflects the accretions to collections as well as oversize materials.
Scope and Contents
The NYU Abu Dhabi Publications and Ephemera collection is the primary collection of NYUAD publications in the University Archives. An accumulating, "living collection," this RG consists of published bulletins, curricula guides, brochures, research reports, commemencement programs, class yearbooks, events catalogs and calendars, faculty and student journals, and other commemorative artifacts and publications that document academic and community life across the NYU Abu Dhabi campus, including research achievements. When available, two copies of each publication have been retained and are preserved as part of this collection. A separate publication duplicates collection is also maintained.
Each series may include more specific information about certain titles, their history and how they were used.
NYU Abu Dhabi; Universities
- Admissions, Recruitment, and General Promotional Materials
  Scope and Contents
  Publications and ephemera related to the University's efforts to recruit faculty and students.
  - Admissions: General Material, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: NYU Abu Dhabi, A Global Education for the Leadership of Tomorrow, 2010-2011 [for AY2011-2012] (Box 1)
  - Admissions: General Material, 2012-2013 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Bidayat at NYU Abu Dhabi, ca. 2015 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Mixed recruitment materials [accumulating] (Box 1)
    Includes:
    NYU Abu Dhabi, What Will You Discover?
    NYU Abu Dhabi, Global Citizenship Starts Here
    Find Yourself At NYU Abu Dhabi
    NYU Abu Dhabi, Are You Ready to Make History?
    Academic Life at NYU Abu Dhabi
  - NYU Abu Dhabi: The Saadiyat Campus, ca. 2014 (Box 1)
  - NYU Abu Dhabi: Facilities Overview, [ca. 2014] (Box 1)
  - Find Yourself at NYU Abu Dhabi [recruitment packet], ca. 2018 (Box 1)
  - New York University Abu Dhabi, An Exceptional Place for Exceptional People: Compensation and Benefits, ca. 2020 [undated] (Box 7)
  - New York University Abu Dhabi, An Exceptional Place for Exceptional People: Faculty, ca. 2020 [undated] (Box 7)
  - New York University Abu Dhabi, An Exceptional Place for Exceptional People: Horizons, At Home in Abu Dhabi, ca. 2020 [undated] (Box 7)
  - The Abu Dhabi Guide: Modern Architecture, 1968-1992. Edited by Pascal Menoret. (Box 7)
    This guide, published by NYU Abu Dhabi's FIND group [Forming Intersections and Dialogues], was often distributed as recruitment or as gifts from External Relations.
    (information provided by Public Affairs and Communications officer Dustin Harris, 2021).
- Students
  This series of publications constitutes materials pertaining to the students of NYU Abu Dhabi, including class yearbooks, Capstone Project summaries and festival programs, commencement exercises, and Ma'a Salama materials. Arranged alphabetically, then by year. Note: Capstone Archives are collected and administered in a separate record group.
  - Capstone Festivals and Publications
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival Program, 2016-2017 (Box 2)
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival Group Exhibition, 2016 (Box 2)
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival Program, 2017 (Box 2)
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival, 2018 (Box 2)
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival, 2019 (Box 2)
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival, 2022 (Box 2)
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival, 2023 (Box 2)
    - Arts and Humanities Capstone Festival, 2024 (Box 2)
    - Capstone Project: Summary, Class of 2015 (Box 2)
    - Capstone Project: Summary, Class of 2016 (Box 2)
    - Capstone Project: Summary, Class of 2017 (Box 2)
    - Capstone Projects: Summary, Class of 2018 (Box 2)
    - Capstone Projects: Summary, Class of 2019 (Box 2)
    - Capstone Projects: Summary, Class of 2020 (Box 2)
    - Capstone Projects: Summary, Class of 2021 (Box 2)
  - Class of 2014
    - Class of 2014 [freshman yearbook] (Box 2)
      "In the first year of New York University's groundbreaking new venture in higher education, 147 impressive students constitute the first-ever freshman class in a first-ever type of Global Network University: NYU Abu Dhabi, The World's Honors College"
    - Marhaba: Upperclass Schedule, 2014 (Box 2)
    - Inaugural Commencement Exercises, 2014 [program] (Box 2)
      May 25, 2014
    - Saariya, Class of 2014 Yearbook (Box 2)
    - We Are The Class of 2014 (Box 2)
    - Life Beyond Saadiyat: Class of 2014 [Career Development Center] (Box 2)
  - Class of 2015
    - Class of 2015 [freshman yearbook] (Box 3)
      "As NYU's groundbreaking venture in higher education enters its second year, 161 talented students join our cosmopolitan community of scholars, bringing their questions, ambitions, and new life into NYU's Global Network University. NYU Abu Dhabi"
    - Marhaba 2015, First Year Schedule, August 24-30 (Box 3)
    - Ma'a Salama, 2015 (Box 3)
    - Commencement Exercises, 2015 [program] (Box 3)
    - Commencement 2015: Printed Email Communications (Box 3)
    - This is the Class of 2015 (Box 3)
    - Saariya, Class of 2015 (Box 3)
    - Life Beyond Saadiyat: Class of 2015 [Career Development Center] (Box 3)
  - Class of 2016
    - Class of 2016 [freshman yearbook] (Box 3)
      "As NYU's groundbreaking venture in higher education enters its third year, 151 talented students join our cosmopolitan community of scholars, bringing their questions, dreams, and a common desire to grow as global citizens. NYU Abu Dhabi."
    - Marhaba 2016 (Box 3)
    - Commencement Exercises, 2016 [program] (Box 3)
    - This is the Class of 2016 (Box 3)
    - Life Beyond Saadiyat, 2016 (Box 3)
  - Class of 2017
    - Class of 2017 [freshman yearbook] (Box 3)
      "As NYU's groundbreaking venture in higher education enters its fourth year, 175 students arrive and bring their diverse talents, intellectual curiosity, and remarkable determination to our commuunity of scholars; their accomplishments and dreams of a cosmopolitan education represent the enduring vision of the world's foremost global university."
    - Class of 2017 [senior yearbook, May 1, 2017] (Box 3)
    - Commencement Exercises, 2017 [program] (Box 4)
    - This is the Class of 2017 (Box 4)
    - Life Beyond Saadiyat, 2017
  - Class of 2018
    - This is the Class of 2018 (Box 4)
    - Commencement Exercises, 2018 (Box 4)
    - Commencement Address 2018, Vice Chancellor Al Bloom (Box 4)
    - Class of 2018 [senior yearbook] (Box 4)
    - Life Beyond Saadiyat, 2018
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Class of 2014-Class of 2018 graduates (Box 4)
  - Class of 2019
    - Commencement 2019 [Folder and Program] (Box 4)
    - Commencement Address 2019, Vice Chancellor Al Bloom (Box 4)
  - Life Beyond Saadiyat, 2014-2019 (Box 4)
  - Class of 2020
    - The Shibboleth [2018-2020] (Box 4)
      Note about this publication, from AY19-20 StuGov President Hafsa Ahmed: In 2018, students were surveyed about their NYUAD experience, including why being an NYUAD student matters, and other questions about their memories and community experiences. Over 450 students responded. From those responses, a student editorial team (who chose to include their initials in final publication) curated the responses along with original illustrations into a book, with a limited print run. From Hafsa Ahmed: "The intent was to preserve, however much possible, the unique values and characteristics of the NYUAD community amidst its rapid change and transitions, for future generations of students. The first distribution of the book took place in Fall 2019 whereby a copy was dropped off outside each first year student's dorm. In Spring 2020, during NYUAD's 10th anniversary, a wider distribution took place among the rest of the student population. This is not something that has been done before and we don't anticipate this to repeat again simply because that will go against the purpose of having one foundational values book for all generations of students to come.
      "A little more about this book - the Shibboleth (that's what we've named it) is extremely student-facing and non-administrative in nature i.e. its themes, production, and distribution have all happened without direct official involvement from any office/institution on this campus (save for Public Affairs who helped manage vendors and VC's office who generously funded this). The value in this values book is that it's largely of and for the student body. At this point we don't anticipate it to be distributed on a large scale to the wider community (save for some individual staff/faculty/admin who are extremely student-facing and drive community-building on our campus). Of course, this may change over the next few years as new students take the charge of handling the Shibboleth (we have internal transition systems in place) but I wanted to share the original intent with [University Archives], especially because I feel strongly that any archiving process should be accompanied by the vision/intent of what it is that's being archived."
    - Class of 2020 Life Beyond Saadiyat (Box 4.1)
  - Class of 2021
    - Write The Sum: Class of 2021 Yearbook (Box 4.1)
    - Commencement 2021
    - Commencement Exercises, 2021 [program]
    - Life Beyond Saadiyat, 2021
  - Class of 2022
    - Life Beyond Saadiyat, 2022
  - Class of 2023
    - Commencement Program, 2023
    - Gold Tassels, NYU Graduation Honors 2023
      Students who reach graduation as a top-ranking Baccalaureate candidate or Baccalaureate graduate are named a "University Honors Scholar" and awarded the NYU Founders' Day Award.
      Recipients of this honor receive a gold tassel to wear during Commencement and a personalized certificate.
      This is a tradition that extends to the NYUAD campus.
      https://www.nyu.edu/students/student-information-and-resources/registration-records-and-graduation/graduation-and-diplomas/graduation-honors.html
  - Class of 2024
    - Class of 2024 Wrapped: Yearbook
    - Commencement Exercises Class of 2024 [program] (Box 4.1)
    - Scattered Words: Poetry Book by Al Diwan SIG (Box 4.1)
  - Science Division Capstone Festival, 2017 (Box 2)
- Research Reports and Published Research Highlights
  Publications that highlight NYU Abu Dhabi research achievements, including annual research reports and research conference publications. Arranged chronologically by year.
  - Activities Report, 2011-2012 (Box 5)
  - Research Report, 2012 (Box 5)
  - Research: Local Relevance, Global Perspective, 2013 (Box 5)
  - Research Report, 2013-2014 (Box 5)
  - Annual Research Conference, February 22-24, 2014 (Box 5)
  - Annual Research Conference, February 28-March 1, 2015 (Box 5)
  - NYU Abu Dhabi Research, 2015-2016 (Box 5)
  - Highlights: UAE Impact, 2015-2016 (Box 5)
  - Research, 2016 (Box 5)
  - UAE Highlights, 2016-2017 (Box 5)
  - Annual Report, Academic Year 2017-2018 (Box 5)
  - Research, 2017 (Box 5)
  - UAE Highlights, 2017-2018 (Box 5)
  - Research Conference, 2018 (Box 6)
  - Research, 2018 (Box 6)
  - UAE Highlights, 2018-2019 (Box 6)
  - Research, 2019 (Box 6)
  - NYU Undergraduate Research, 2019 (Box 6)
  - Manara, Issue 1, 2020 (Box 6)
  - Manara, Issue 2, 2021 (Box 6)
  - Manara, Issue 3, 2023 (Box 6)
  - Manara, Issue 4, 2024 (Box 6)
- Core Curricula Information
  Published descriptions of courses and the core curricula offered at NYU Abu Dhabi. Arranged chronologically. Other related materials include web-based course descriptions, which are preserved in New York as part of the NYU University Archives. Note: is anticipated that these publications will transition to electronic only after the 2020-2021 academic year.
  - Core Curriculum User Guide, 2016-2017 (Box 7)
  - Core Curriculum User Guide, 2017-2018 (Box 7)
  - Core Curriculum User Guide, 2018-2019 (Box 7)
  - Core Curriculum User Guide, 2019-2020 (Box 7)
  - Core Curriculum User Guide, 2021-2022 (Box 7)
    General
    *includes appendix with stickers
  - Core Curriculum Guide, 2023-2024 (Box 7)
- Campus Bulletins
  - Preview of Academic Programs, 2010-2011 (Box 8)
  - Bulletin 2010-2011 (Box 8)
  - Bulletin 2012-2013 (Box 8)
  - Bulletin 2013-2014 (Box 8)
  - Bulletin 2014-2015 (Box 8)
  - Bulletin 2015-2016 (Box 9)
  - Bulletin 2016-2017 (Box 9)
  - Bulletin 2017-2018 (Box 9)
  - Bulletin 2018-2019 (Box 9)
  - Bulletin 2019-2020 (Box 10)
  - Bulletin 2020-2021 (Box 10)
  - Bulletin 2021-2022 (Box 10)
  - Bulletin 2022-2023 (Box 10)
  - [Hold for 2023-2024 and next three years] (Box 11)
- Divisional Publications and NYUAD Disciplinary Journals
  [REPROCESSING IN PROGRESS]
  - Arts and Humanities Division
    - Arts Program (Box 12)
    - Dhakira Center for Heritage Studies: New Interdisciplinary Minor in Heritage Studies (Box 12)
    - Film and New Media Program (Box 12)
    - Mending Our Ways: Student Wayfinding Proposals [Research Kitchen Publication], 2021 (Box 12)
    - Music Program (Box 12)
    - NYUAD Open Studios (Box 12, Map-case 1.C)
      See also oversize
    - Theater Program (Box 12)
    - Year in Review 2017 (Box 12)
    - Year in Review 2018 (Box 12)
  - Engineering Division
    - 1st NYU Biomedical & Biosystems Conference, April 11, 2017 (Box 12)
    - 4th NYUAD Transportation Symposium, November 18-19, 2018 (Box 12)
    - 3rd International Symposium on Infrastructure Asset Management, March 31-April 1, 2019 (Box 12)
  - Science Division
  - Social Science Division
    - NYU Abu Dhabi Journal of Social Sciences: Showcase of Exemplary Student Works, Fall 2013 (Box 12)
  - Journals
    - Journals (NYUAD): A New Look At Heritage, History and Memory in the UAE by students of New York University Abu Dhabi, Spring 2014 (Box 13)
    - Journals (NYUAD): Analysis and Impression, Fall 2013 (Box 13)
    - Journals (NYUAD): Airport Road, A Journal of Student Creative Work, Issues 01-08, and Issue 10, 2014-2018, Fall 2019 (Box 13)
    - Journals (NYUAD): Electra Street, A Journal of the Arts and Humanities, Issues 01, 02, 2014-2015, and Issue 04, Winter 2020 (Box 13)
    - Journals (NYUAD): Exit 11, A Journal of the First Year Writing Seminar, 2016-2017 and 2017-2018 (Box 13)
    - Journals (NYUAD): Food in the Global Kitchen: J-Term 2014 (Box 13)
    - Journals (NYUAD): Urbanism of Hamdan Street, 2014 (Box 13)
- Publications and Ephemera from Campus Centers, Departments, Galleries, Programs, and Special Events
  - Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Scholars Program: Yearbook, Class of 2008-2009 (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Scholars Program: Yearbook, Class of 2009-2010 (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Scholars Program: Best of Class of 2009-2010 [Photo CD] (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Scholars Program: Recruitment Video 2010 [DVD] (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Scholars Program: Yearbook, Class of 2010-2011 (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Scholars Program: Yearbook, Class of 2011-2012 (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Scholars Program [brochure], 2012-2013 (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Scholars Program: Yearbook, Class of 2014-2015 (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Scholars Program: Yearbook, Class of 2015-2016 (Box 14)
  - Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Scholars Program: Five Years of Reflections and Memories, 2013 (Box 15)
  - Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Scholars Program: Celebrating A Decade of Excellence, 2018 (Box 15)
  - The NYUAD Summer Academy: 2011, Summer I Report (Box 15)
  - The NYUAD Summer Academy: 2012 Classbook (Box 15)
  - The NYUAD Summer Academy: 2014 Classbook (Box 15)
  - NYUAD 10th Anniversary: Here, We Grow: Celebrating Ten Years of Excellence, Innovation, and Engagement in the UAE and Beyond, 2010-2020 (Box 16)
  - NYUAD 10th Anniversary: The Origin Story: An Oral History of the Founding of NYU Abu Dhabi 2005-2010 (Box 16)
  - Admissions Publicity: NYU Quarterly, 2016-2017 (Box 17)
  - Arts Center Ephemera (Box 17)
  - Arts Center: Seasons, 2015 - (Map-case 1.C)
  - Arts Center: Building A Performing Arts Community on Saadiyat Island. Stories of and from The Arts Center at NYU Abu Dhabi (Box 19)
  - Campus Life Leadership Awards, 2017 [May 10, 2017] (Box 17)
  - Campus Safety Emergency Contacts (Box 17)
  - Career Development Center [Student Affairs/Campus Life] (Box 17)
  - Career Development: Ultimate Career Guidance, 2019-2020 (Box 17)
  - Community Outreach [Student Affairs/Campus Life] (Box 17)
  - Community Outreach: Earthquake Relief Volunteering, 2023 (Box 17)
  - Crystal Growth Symposium, May 5th, 2014 (Box 17)
  - Dean of Students 2013-2014 NYUAD Planner (Box 17)
  - Design Collective, Design Journal 2021 (Box 17)
  - Economics Professional Development Program, September 2014 (Box 17)
  - Executive Education (Box 17)
  - Generative AI and NYU, August 2023 (Box 17)
  - Global Education [Office of] (Box 17)
  - Guide to Biking on Saadiyat Island, n.d. [Student Affairs/Campus Life] (Box 17)
  - Howler Radio (Box 17)
  - Leave the Mic Open: 4 Years of Writing for Open Mics and NYUAD [by Yannick Trapman-O'Brien] (Box 18)
  - Library, 2014 - [brochures] (Box 18)
  - Live the Possibilities [Student Affairs/Campus Life] (Box 18)
  - NYUAD Community Life: Kids and Family Resources, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Reframing Museums: A Louvre Abu Dhabi and NYUAD Symposium, November 16-18, 2020 (Box 18)
  - Residential Education: Life on the Highline [Student Affairs/Campus Life] (Box 18)
  - Residential Education: The Ultimate Guide, Living on NYUAD Saadiyat Campus, the Highline, Abu Dhabi, What to Do, Where, Maps and More, n.d. [Student Affairs/Campus Life] (Box 18)
  - RealAD Show Program, 2013; 2019 (Box 18)
  - "Scene/Seen," NYU Quarterly Magazine for Prospective Students ca. 2019 [NYUAD spotlight] (Box 18)
  - SIG-related Ephemera [Student Interest Groups] (Box 18)
  - Social Responsibility, Office of, "Our 10-Year Highlights," 2021 (Box 18)
  - Special Olympics IX Mena Games, Abu Dhabi: NYUAD Welcomes You, March 14-23, 2018 (Box 18)
  - TEDx NYUAD, April 13, 2019 (Box 18)
  - UAE Energy Forum, January 8, 2020 (Box 18)
  - UAE National Day ephemera (Box 18)
  - What Does It Mean to Belong? Storybook by NYUAD alumnus Maryam Khalifa Al Shehhi [Arabic] (Box 18)
  - Where is Our Home? Storybook by NYUAD SIG ElevatED (Box 18)
- Non-NYUAD Publications/Collaborative Partnerships
  - Abu Dhabi Creative Media Competition (Box 20)
  - Abu Dhabi Ideas Weekend, 2018 - 2019 (Box 20)
  - Atlas Magazine, Etihad Airways, September 2019 (Box 20)
  - Abu Dhabi Film Festival at NYUAD, 2013 (Box 20)
  - General Non-NYUAD (Box 20)
  - NYU Shanghai, Brochures (Box 20)
  - Lest We Forget: Marhaba Abu Dhabi [binder book of reprinted postcards] (Box 20)
  - 25 Years of Arab Creativity: Abu Dhabi Festival, 2013 (Box 20)
  - The Present: Contemporary Art from the Emirates (Box 20)
  - Abu Dhabi Music and Arts Foundation, September 2013-December 2014 (Box 20)
- Artifacts
  Although 3-D objects and physical artifacts are not generally collected by the Archives, some materials such as t-shirts, pins, buttons and other physical promotional materials are part of the collection.
  - Capstone Arts Festival Tee Shirt, 2017 (Box A1)
  - NYUAD Purple Polo T-Shirt (Box A1)
  - NYUAD Foam Finger (Box A1)
  - NYUAD Denim Tote Bag - [contest winner] (Box A1)
  - NYUAD plain canvas tote bag (Box A1)
  - NYUAD Here, We Grow Canvas Tote Bag (10th Anniversary) (Box A1)
  - NYUAD Bookstore Items: NYUAD Tumblers (Box A2)
  - NYUAD Bookstore Items: Various Notebooks and Notepads [old logo included] (Box A2)
  - NYUAD Giveaways: Sunglasses, Fan, Pen (Box A2)
  - Class of 2014 Reunion Artifacts (Box A3)
  - Commencement 2024, Stand-in Diploma and Speech Cards (Box A4)
  - Alumni Reunion 2024 wrist band (Box A4)
  - NYUAD silk scarf giveaway (Box A4)